Guide to the Croswell Bowen Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Croswell Bowen papers
1880-1967
1928-1964
YCAL MSS 2
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
7.5
(10 boxes)
The papers contain some professional correspondence, manuscripts, typescripts, and printed copies of many of Bowen's works, and subject files.
Other Storage Formats: oversize
Bowen, Croswell, 1905-1971
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Unspecified, please consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
CROSWELL BOWEN (1905-1971)
Croswell Bowen was born in 1905 and was graduated from Yale in 1929. After traveling in Europe and studying at the Sorbonne, he returned to the United States and worked as a newspaper reporter and as a freelance magazine writer. His first book, Great River of the Mountains: the Hudson, was published in 1940. He joined the American Field Service as an official photographer in 1941, was wounded during the battle of Tobruk in 1942, and received the Africa Star and the British Empire Medal.
During the 1940s Bowen reported for PM, often on crime and juvenile delinquency. In 1948 he joined the staff of the New Yorker. His book on criminals and delinquents, They Went Wrong, was published in 1954, followed by his biography of A. Oakey Hall. Bowen's biography of Eugene O'Neill, The Curse of the Misbegotten, was written with the assistance of Shane O'Neill and published in 1959. In 1962 Bowen joined the staff of the trade magazine Madison Avenue, leaving in 1964 to become Director of Information at Compton Advertising.
Croswell Bowen married Marjorie Luce Hill, a Vassar graduate, in 1944. The couple had three daughters, Betsy, Lucey, and Molly Patricia, and one son, Peter, who died before his second birthday. The Bowens were divorced in 1966. Croswell Bowen died on July 15, 1971.
Scope and Contents
The Croswell Bowen Papers span the dates 1880-1966, and document some of the professional activities of Croswell Bowen. The collection consists of three series. Series I, Correspondence, is housed in Box 1 and contains alphabetically arranged correspondence. Letters from unidentified writers have been placed at the end of the series. The correspondence is entirely business-related, with the exception of a small group of letters Bowen received in 1928 concerning an undergraduate research project in which he asked literary figures to compare Harvard men and Yale men. Respondents include James Rowland Angell, Henry Emerson Fosdick, H. L. Mencken, Edwin Arlington Robinson, Upton Sinclair, Ida Tarbell, and William Lyon Phelps, who suggested that the Yale man is "more downright, straightforward, and a little more naive."
The remaining letters pertain to Bowen's career as a writer. Correspondents include Bowen's publishers Bobbs-Merrill, Hastings House, and Oxford University Press; magazines for which he freelanced, including Coronet, Hudson River Magazine, Mademoiselle, Pageant, and Reader's Digest; and prospective subjects of articles, including Felix Frankfurter, Sigurd Larmon, Eleanor Roosevelt, and Robert A. Stranahan. Bowen's research for his first book, The Hudson, is documented in his 1938 correspondence with Carl Carmer. Although Bowen is best-known for his biography of Eugene O'Neill, the collection contains no correspondence with any member of the O'Neill family, and only two letters by Alexander Renner provide biographical information on O'Neill. Several correspondents do mention The Curse of the Misbegotten, including Barbara Battelle, Guy Hamelin, and Sister Mary Madelena.
Series II, Writings, is located in Boxes 2-4 and is divided into two alphabetically arranged sections, Books and Shorter Works. The Books section includes reviews of The Elegant Oakey and They Went Wrong, as well as publicity and photographs for The Hudson: Great River of the Mountains. Incomplete notes, draft typescripts, and galleys of Bowen's biography of Eugene O'Neill, The Curse of the Misbegotten, are located in Box 2, folders 33-43.
Shorter Works is divided into Articles, Book Reviews, and Scrapbooks. The numerous articles by Bowen illustrate his interests as a journalist. They include interviews with and reports on political figures such as Adlai Stevenson III, John F. Kennedy, Trygve Lie, and Douglas MacArthur; a series of profiles of advertising executives published in Madison Avenue; and a variety of human-interest stories such as "The Shy Cop Who Saw Two Flying Saucers." Bowen also contributed popular history articles such as "The Great Red Scare of 1920" and a biographical sketch of Lafcadio Hearn, "Death Unites Oriental and Yankee Who Went Buddhist for Love."
Bowen was best-known, however, as a crime reporter, and his work in this area is well-represented in the collection. The series contains copies of many of his articles on these topics, including two "Annals of Crime" columns from the New Yorker, his reports on the Brinks robbery, and articles on juvenile delinquency, shoplifting, and embezzlements.
Several of these crime articles appeared in Pageant magazine, to which Bowen frequently contributed during the 1950s. His report for them on the hazards of radiation, "The New Invisible Death Around Us," won the Benjamin Franklin Magazine Citation Award in 1956. Articles also contains the manuscript of "Poet into Historian," an appreciation of Carl Carmer, and proofs and galleys of "The Greatest Tragedy of Eugene O'Neill."
Book Reviews by Bowen are located in Box 4, folders 114-21, and include his review of Birdman of Alcatraz by Thomas A. Gaddis and of two books by John Bartlow Martin. The Scrapbooks of clippings, located in Box 9, folders 192-93, contain numerous signed and unsigned newspaper articles, mostly from PM.
Box 5 holds Series III, Personal Papers, which are alphabetically arranged. The series includes a high-schools yearbook of Shane O'Neill's; a portrait of Bowen taken by Margaret Bourke-White; publicity for the 1938 radio show, "Information Please;" and drafts of three articles by Carl Carmer.
Series IV, Printed Material, includes single issues of magazines, a bound volume of PM's Picture News, seven folders of Madison Avenue issues from the years 1958-63, and a pamphlet on the "Motion Picture Industry in War-Time America: 1943-1944."
Oversize material is located in Boxes 7-10 and has been arranged in series order. Included are eleven folders of photographs for Great River of the Mountains, scrapbooks of clippings, and a portrait of Croswell Boswen.
Other papers concerning the professional activities of Croswell Bowen are located at Choate-Rosemary Hall.
Authors and publishers; Crime in mass media; Crime and the press; Educational surveys; Juvenile delinquency -- Case studies; Police and the press; Universities and surveys -- United States; Hudson River (N.Y. and N.J.); Journalists; Bourke-White, Margaret, 1904-1971; Bowen, Croswell, 1905-1971; Carmer, Carl, 1893-1976; Frankfurter, Felix, 1882-1965; O'Neill, Eugene, 1888-1953; O'Neill, Shane Rudraighe, 1919-1977; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962; Yale College (1887- ). Class of 1929
- Correspondence, 1928-64; Series I; 0.25' (1 box)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Correspondence, is housed in Box 1 and consists of alphabetically arranged correspondence.
  - American Magazine, 1932-34 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Andrews, Mary Raymond, [1928?] May 25
  - Angell, James Rowland, 1928 Jun 28
  - Barrett, Walter, 1962 Feb 6 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Basso, Hamilton, 1960 Jan 28
  - Battelle, Barbara, 1963 April 29
  - Bernson, Mary, 1963 Mar 5
  - Blaik, Colonel, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bludworth, H. W., n.d.
  - Bobbs-Merrill Co., 1960
  - Borden, Neil, 1962 Jun 28
  - Bradford, Roark, 1941, n.d.
  - Carmer, Carl, 1938-62, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Chamberlain, Dorothy (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Charles Scribner's Sons, 1945 Jan 12
  - Clark, Barrett, 1961 May 3
  - Compton Advertising Co., 1958, n.d.
  - Conklin, Margaret, 1928 Jun 28
  - Coronet, 1960 Jun 27
  - Dartmouth College, 1959 Apr 29 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Des Moines Register, 1959 Apr 23
  - Don-Byrne, Brian, 1928 Jun 19
  - Dutton and Co., 1943 Apr 26
  - Erskine, John, 1928 May 24 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ferber, Edna, 1928 May 22
  - Fosdick, Henry Emerson, 1928 May 26
  - Frankfurter, Felix, 1945-56, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Goodbody, Garrett, 1961 Mar 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Good Housekeeping, 1960 May 11
  - Hagerty, James, 1961 Feb 15 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Hamelin, Guy, 1960 Nov 15
  - Harcourt, Brace and Co., 1928 May 26
  - Harriman, Averell, 1957 May 27
  - Hastings House, 1942, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Havell, George, 1934 Dec 4
  - Hayakawa, Sessue, 1960
  - Houghton, Carolyn Wells, [1928] (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Hudson River Magazine, 1941
  - Keogh, Andrew, 1928 Jun 26 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Kimple, Louis, 1961, n.d.
  - Larmon, Sigurd, 1958-59 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Related Archival Materials note
    See also: National Probation and Parole Association
  - Leamy, Hugh, [1929] Jul 25 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - London Express Features, 1959 Oct 27
  - Lull, Richard, 1928 Jun 22
  - Lynes, Russell, n.d.
  - McBride, Mary Margaret, 1941 Jun 30 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - McCoy, Esther, 1928 May 31
  - McGraw-Hill Co., 1959-63, n.d.
  - McNulty, Thomas, 1963 Aug 13 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Madelena, Sister Mary, 1958 May 26
  - Mademoiselle, 1961 Feb 20
  - Maxwell, William, 1961 Feb 17
  - Mellon, Paul, 1957 May 7 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Mencken, H. L., 1928 May 25
  - Miele, Elizabeth, 1933 Aug 21
  - Mulligan, William, 1963 Aug 9
  - National Probation and Parole Association, 1959 May 6 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Neff, Mary Alice, n.y. Sep 20
  - The New Republic, 1964 Jun 5
  - The New York Post, 1945 Jan 24
  - O'Hearn, S. M., 1964 May 15 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - O'Shanahan, Frank, 1961 Jan 31
  - Oxford University Press, 1957-61
  - Pageant, 1957-64 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Patterson, Alicia, 1962 Sep 18
  - Phelps, William Lyon, 1928 May 29
  - Phillips, Barbara and John, 1958 Mar 26
  - Pitt-Smith, Katherine, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Platt-Monk Co., 1959 May 4
  - Post, Langdon W., 1935
  - Powers, Edward, 1958
  - Radovic, Ljerka, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Random House, 1944 Dec 20
  - Reader's Digest, 1957, 1961
  - Redbook, 1960, 1961
  - Renner, Alexander, 1957-58 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Reinhart, Jean, 1932 Mar 18
  - Robinson, Edwin Arlington, 1928 Jun 22
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1945, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Russell, Walter, 1945 Oct 30
  - The Saturday Evening Post, 1960 Jun 30 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Shriver, Eunice, 1966 Jul 15
  - Sinclair, Upton, 1928 Jun 27
  - Snow, Edgar, 1944 Apr 18 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Sosenko, Anna, 1945 Jan 16
  - Stevenson, Adlai E., 1952
  - Stranahan, Robert A., 1932
  - Tarbell, Ida M., 1928 Jun 28 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Tarkington, S., 1928 Jun 21
  - Terhune, Albert P., 1928 Jun 19
  - Thomas, Norman, 1942 Nov 28
  - United Press International, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Wetzel, Malcolm, 1954 Mar 9
  - Whitney, John Hay, n.d.
  - Wilder, Thornton, 1928 May 24 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Willkie, Wendell, 1941 April 1
  - Wolfe, Linda, 1962 Nov 20
  - Wylie, Max, 1957 Apr 12
  - Young, Robert, Jr., 1960 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Yudkoff, Alvin, n.y. Feb 15
  - Unidentified, 1935-64, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Writings, 1932-67; Series II; 1.5' (3 boxes)
  Series II, Writings, is housed in Boxes 2-4 and has been organized in two sections, Books, and Shorter Works, which is divided into Articles and Book Reviews. Material in each section is alphabetically arranged by title.
  - BOOKS
    - Curse of the Misbegotten
      - Research information, 1957 Sep 26 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - Notes and drafts (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - Drafts, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 35-41)
      - Galley proofs, incomplete, [1958] (Box 2, Folder 42)
      - Dust covers, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - The Elegant Oakey
      - Hall, A. Oakey: autographs, [1880?] (Box 2, Folder 44)
      - Reviews, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 45)
      - Publicity, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Great River of the Mountains
      - Dust covers, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 47)
      - Photographs
        See: Oversize, Box 7, folders 156-66
      - Publicity, 1941, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      - Review, draft, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - They Went Wrong
      - Dust cover, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 50)
      - Review, 1954 Apr 12 (Box 2, Folder 51)
      - Scrapbook
        See: Oversize, Box 7, folder 167
  - SHORTER WORKS
    - Articles
      - "Ahab in Seersucker," PM's Sunday Picture News
        See: Oversize, Box 8, folder 168
      - "Adlai III," New Yorker, 1952 Oct 11 (Box 3, Folder 52)
      - "America's Crime Problem," The Listener
        See: Oversize, Box 8, folder 169
      - "The "Americanization of J. Parnell Thomas," PM's Sunday Picture News
        See: Oversize, Box 8, folder 170
      - "Annals of Crime I," New Yorker, 1952 Nov 1 (Box 3, Folder 53)
      - "Annals of Crime II," New Yorker, 1952 Nov 8 (Box 3, Folder 54)
      - "Arthur B. Langlie, McCall Corporation," Madison Avenue, 1959 Feb (Box 3, Folder 55)
      - "At the Helm of the Streamline Era-- Raymond Loewy," DAC News (Box 3, Folder 56)
      - "Bate's Rudolph Montgelas," Madison Avenue, 1959 Jul (Box 3, Folder 57)
      - "The Boy Next Door," Cosmopolitan, 1953 Sep (Box 3, Folder 58)
      - "Bristol Meyer's Lee H. Bristol," Madison Avenue, 1959 Sep (Box 3, Folder 59)
      - "Camera Over the Desert," The Villager, 1944 Mar (Box 3, Folder 60)
      - "The Case of the Sadistic Cop," Men In Danger, 1955 Sep (Box 3, Folder 61)
      - "Chronicler of Crime," The Saturday Review, 1956 Apr 28 (Box 3, Folder 62)
      - "Church Bomber," proofs, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 63)
      - "Clubmanship," Madison Avenue, 1963 Apr (Box 3, Folder 64)
      - "Colgate-Palmolive's E. H. Little," Madison Avenue, 1959 Apr (Box 3, Folder 65)
      - "Compton's Bart Cummings," Madison Avenue, 1959 Nov (Box 3, Folder 66)
      - "Congress' Bouting Thomas," PM's Sunday Picture News
        See: Oversize, Box 8, folder 171
      - "Cross Bows But No Non-piloted Aircraft," PM's Sunday Picture News, 1947 Aug 3 (Box 3, Folder 67)
      - "Cunningham and Walsh's Jack Cunningham," Madison Avenue, 1959 March (Box 3, Folder 68)
      - "Darcy's Robert M. Ganger," Madison Avenue, 1959 Jun (Box 3, Folder 69)
      - "DDB's Doyle, Dane and Bernbach," Madison Avenue, 1959 Aug (Box 3, Folder 70)
      - "Death Unites Oriental and Yankee Who Went Buddhist for Love", 1932 Apr 3 (Box 3, Folder 71)
      - "Dum De Dum Dum," Seventeen
        See: Oversize, Box 8, folder 172
      - "The Earnest Volunteers Whose Firehouse Burned," PM's Sunday Picture News, 1947 Aug 10 (Box 3, Folder 72)
      - "Erwin Wasey, Ruthrauf and Ryan's David B. Williams," Madison Avenue, 1960 Jan (Box 3, Folder 73)
      - "An Evening with Two Gentlemen," PM's Sunday Picture News
        See: Oversize, Box 8, folder 173
      - "Exchanges, Quotations in Wall Street Strike," PM's Sunday Picture News, 1948 Apr 4 (Box 3, Folder 74)
      - "Ex-Moscow Writer Looks Over His Shoulder," PM's Sunday Picture News, 1948 May 2 (Box 3, Folder 75)
      - "George C. Marshall of Uniontown, PA," PM's Sunday Picture News
        See: Oversize, Box 8, folder 174
      - "The Great Brinks Robbery," Daily Mirror
        See: Oversize, Box 8, folder 175
      - "The Great Red Scare of 1920," PM's Sunday Picture News
        See: Oversize, Box 8, folder 176
      - "The Greatest Tragedy of Eugene O'Neill," mixed proofs and galleys
        See: Oversize, Box 8, folder 177
      - "A Greenville Lynch Case Lawyer Explains," PM's Sunday Picture News, 1947 Jul 27 (Box 4, Folder 76)
      - "Guide to Clubs," galley, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 77)
      - "H. W. Ross," The New Yorker, 1951 Dec 15 (Box 4, Folder 78)
      - "Hartley Twins," Pageant, 1954 Jun (Box 4, Folder 79)
      - "Hereinafters and Whereases, Lights, Action, Camera," PM's Sunday Picture News
        See: Oversize, Box 8, folder 178
      - "How Dear Miss Minnie Stole $3,000,000," Pageant, 1956 Sep (Box 4, Folder 80)
      - "How Leaders in the Cold War Looked as the Word Barrage Began in the UN," PM's Sunday Picture News
        See: Oversize, Box 8, folder 179
      - "How to Locate A Neighborhood Bookie and Place a Two-buck Horse-race Bet," PM's Sunday Picture News, 1947 Jul 27 (Box 4, Folder 81)
      - "I-Like-Ike for President GHQ Purrs Smooth and Easy as a Rolls Royce," PM's Sunday Picture News
        See: Oversize, Box 8, folder 180
      - "Jack Kennedy at Choate," New York Post, 1967 May 27 (Box 4, Folder 82)
      - "John Brown's Body," Yale Alumni Magazine, 1960 Jun (Box 4, Folder 83)
      - "Kenyon and Eckhardt's Bill Lewis," Madison Avenue, 1959 Dec (Box 4, Folder 84)
      - "'Ladies and Gentlemen, the President of the United States,'" PM's Sunday Picture News
        See: Oversize, Box 8, folder 181
      - "A Legion Official Defines Horseplay," PM's Sunday Picture News, 1947 Aug 24 (Box 4, Folder 85)
      - "Louis G. Cowan, President of CBS TV Network," Madison Avenue, 1959 Jan (Box 4, Folder 86)
      - "MacArthur a Day Ahead of Other Candidates," PM's Sunday Picture News, 1948 Apr 4 (Box 4, Folder 87)
      - "McCann - Erickson's Marion Harper, Jr.," Madison Avenue, 1958 Nov (Box 4, Folder 88)
      - "McFeely Meets His Match," PM's Sunday Picture News
        See: Oversize, Box 8, folder 182
      - "Mr. and Mrs. Erskine Caldwell," draft (Box 4, Folder 89)
      - "A Mourner for the Lonely Spinster Whose Will Is a Suspected Forgery," PM's Sunday Picture News
        See: Oversize, Box 8, folder 183
      - "The New Invisible Death Around Us," Pageant, 1956 Nov (Box 4, Folder 90)
      - "Night in the Municipal Lodging House," PM's Sunday Picture News
        See: Oversize, Box 8, folder 184
      - "NYC Prepares for UNO," PM's Sunday Picture News
        See: Oversize, Box 8, folder 185
      - "Ogilvy, Benson and Mather's David Ogilvy," Madison Avenue, 1958 Dec (Box 4, Folder 91)
      - "Poet into Historian," drafts (Box 4, Folder 92)
      - "Poet into Historian," notes and fragments (Box 4, Folder 93)
      - "Poet into Historian," proofs, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 94)
      - "Reporter at Large. The Outside," The New Yorker, 1952 Oct 18 (Box 4, Folder 95)
      - "Rich Men Over Fifty Kill Selves for Lack of Woman Attention!", 1932 Apr 24 (Box 4, Folder 96)
      - "The Riddle of the Over Generous Banker," Pageant, 1957 Jun (Box 4, Folder 97)
      - "Schenley's Lewis S. Rosenstiel," Madison Avenue, 1959 Oct (Box 4, Folder 98)
      - "Science Discovers Witches in 1957," Pageant, 1957 Feb (Box 4, Folder 99)
      - "Semantic Counts and Thirty Definitions of Fascism," PM's Sunday Picture News, 1947 Dec 7 (Box 4, Folder 100)
      - "Shoplifters," galleys, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 101)
      - "The Shy Cop Who Saw Two Flying Saucers," PM's Sunday Picture News, 1947 Jul 13 (Box 4, Folder 102)
      - "Sidelong Glance at a Profiler," PM's Sunday Picture News
        See: Oversize, Box 8, folder 186
      - "The Smiling Cop Who Heads the Legion," PM's Sunday Picture News
        See: Oversize, Box 8, folder 187
      - "Socking Saga of Jersey Joe," PM's Sunday Picture News
        See: Oversize, Box 8, folder 188
      - "Some Random Facts About Trygve Lie," PM's Sunday Picture News, 1946 Mar 24 (Box 4, Folder 103)
      - "Staten Island Smiths Agree with P. Henry," PM's Sunday Picture News, 1947 Jun 29 (Box 4, Folder 104)
      - "Suppose You Take $5,000 Down to Wall Sreet," PM's Sunday Picture News, 1948 Feb 22 (Box 4, Folder 105)
      - "Times Square Kid," Deadline Detective, 1953 Apr (Box 4, Folder 106)
      - "Times Square Kid," New Yorker, 1950 Feb 18 (Box 4, Folder 107)
      - "Ugo Carusi, New Refugee Co-ordinator Knows the Greatfulness of Immigrants," PM's Sunday Picture News, 1947 Aug 24 (Box 4, Folder 108)
      - "The Unfree Press Finds Everything Is Apple-pie Hospitable in Newburgh Jail," PM's Sunday Picture News, 1948 Mar 7 (Box 4, Folder 109)
      - "USSR Thumbs Rule Book in Old Publicity Game," PM's Sunday Picture News, 1947 Oct 5 (Box 4, Folder 110)
      - "Utopia in the Catskills," PM's Sunday Picture News
        See: Oversize, Box 8, folder 189
      - "When Will Mihai Regain His Throne?" PM's Sunday Picture News, 1948 Mar 14 (Box 4, Folder 111)
      - "You Won't Be Father to Me," The American Weekly, 1955 Apr 17 (Box 4, Folder 112)
      - "Young and Rubicam's Sigurd S. Larmon," Madison Avenue, 1959 May (Box 4, Folder 113)
      - "Young Man in Quest of Peace," PM's Sunday Picture News
        See: Oversize, Box 8, folder 190
    - Book Reviews
      - Beckhardt, Israel: The Violators, 1954 Oct 10 (Box 4, Folder 114)
      - Chute, Charles Lionel and Marjorie Bell: Crime, Courts and Probation, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 115)
      - Fox, Vernon: Violence Behind Bars, 1956 Nov 11 (Box 4, Folder 116)
      - Freeman, Long: "Before I Kill More...", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 117)
      - Gaddis, Thomas E.: Birdman of Alcatraz, 1955 Oct 2 (Box 4, Folder 118)
      - Martin, John Bartlow: Break Down the Walls, 1954 May 30 (Box 4, Folder 119)
      - Martin, John Bartlow: Why Did They Kill?, 1953 Mar 15 (Box 4, Folder 120)
      - Tullet, Tom: Portrait of a Bad Man, 1956 Nov 18 (Box 4, Folder 121)
    - Scrapbooks
      See: Oversize, Box 9, folders 192-93
- Personal Papers, 1925-61; Series III; 0.25' (1 box)
  Box 5 contains Series III, Personal Papers, which has been arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - Artwork
    Cartoon by Eric Godal
    See: Oversize, Box 10, folder 194
    - Cartoon by O. Soglow, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 122)
    - Sketches, 1925, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 123)
  - Biographical information, 1941-61, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 124)
  - Miscellaneous clippings, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 125)
  - O'Neill, Shane: high-school yearbook, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 126)
  - Photographs:
    Bowen, Croswell
    - Portrait by Margaret Bourke-White, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 127)
    - See also: Oversize, Box 10, folder 195
    - Unidentified statue See: Oversize, Box 10, folder 196
    - Yale Class of '29 reunion portrait See: Oversize, Box 10, folder 196
  - Publicity for "Information Please" radio show, [1938] (Box 5, Folder 128)
  - Writings of others
    - Carmer, Carl
      - "Cavalcade of American Legend" (Box 5, Folder 129)
      - Introduction to Bowen's The Hudson, [1941?]
      - "River Packet to New Orleans," drafts, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 130)
    - Churchill, Allen: Article draft, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 131)
    - McGinley, Arthur P.
      - "The Most Unforgettable Character I've Ever Met," notes and drafts (Box 5, Folder 132-33)
- Printed Material, 1919-64; Series IV; 0.5' (1 box)
  Printed Material, Series IV, has been arranged alphabetically by type of material, and within each section alphabetically by title.
  - MAGAZINES
    - Best Sellers, 1958 Oct 1 (Box 6, Folder 134)
    - Ireland of the Welcomes ( Fáilte Romhat go h-Éirinn ) v.13 no.4, 19?? Nov-Dec (Box 6, Folder 135)
    - Madison Avenue, 1958-63 (Box 6, Folder 136-42)
    - Men, 1955 Jul (Box 6, Folder 143)
    - The Nation, 1945 Dec 1 (Box 6, Folder 144)
    - The New York Star v.1 no.186
      See: Oversize, Box 10, folder 197
    - PM v.1 no.1
      See: Oversize, Box 10, folder 198
    - PM's Picture News
      See: Oversize, Box 10, folder 199
    - Publisher's Weekly v.146 no. 11, 1944 Sep 9 (Box 6, Folder 145)
    - Punch, 1954 Apr 7 (Box 6, Folder 146)
    - Real, 1955 Sep (Box 6, Folder 147)
  - PAMPHLETS
    - Calas Tout Chauds, 1928 (Box 6, Folder 148)
    - "Monocle" v.6 no. 2, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 149)
    - Motion Picture Industry in War-time America: 1943-1944, 1944 Mar 27 (Box 6, Folder 150)
    - US vs. Jay Willard Robinson, 1919 Jun 20 (Box 6, Folder 151)
    - "War in Africa"
      See: Oversize, Box 10, folder 200
    - The Wrought Iron Railings of Le Vieux Carré, New Orleans, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 152)
  - PLAYBILLS
    - Maxine Elliott's Theatre, 1935 Jul 29 (Box 6, Folder 153)